フー 六尾の封印
一丁あがりっと。
Sealing of the Six-Tails...
is done.
やっぱ ５人だと
時間がかかるよね。
It takes time when
there are five of us.
(鬼鮫)残りの尾獣は
あと２匹ですか。
There are two Tailed-Beasts left.
あぁ 八尾の回収には
サスケを向かわせている。
Yes... I've sent Sasuke to go
and retrieve the Eight-Tails.
(小南)大丈夫なの？
Can we trust him?
サスケは オレが保障しよう。
I can vouch for Sasuke.
((イタチ : お前が１人なのは
知っている。
I know that you're alone.
なぜ 逃げない？
So why don't you run?
フッ！ オレの人数は
１人から1000人までだぜ。
Hah! My numbers can go
from one to a thousand!
それに 逃げるわけねえだろ。
Besides, I can't run away!
お前を捕まえりゃ
サスケに会えんだからな。
If I capture you,
I get to see Sasuke!
なぜ そこまで弟にこだわる？
Why are you so attached
to my brother?
アイツは 抜け忍だろう？
He's a Rogue Ninja.
少なくとも お前なんかより➡
That's because unlike you...
アイツのことを
兄弟だと思っているからだ！
I think of him as a brother more
than you ever would.
(イタチ)お前はすでに 幻術の中だ。
You're already under my genjutsu.
クソッ！
Damn it!
もう一度 言おう。
I'll say it again.
お前と少し 話がしたいだけだ。
I just wanted to talk to you
for a moment.
お前は
サスケを連れ戻したがっていたな？
You've been trying to take
Sasuke back to the village.
だが…
上手くいかなかったら どうする？
But what if it doesn't go
the way you want?
どうやってでも 連れ戻す！
I'll do anything to
make it happen.
無理やりにでもか？
Even by force?
運よく サスケが
おとなしく里に帰れば➡
If by some turn of luck,
Sasuke goes with you willingly, great.
確かに それでいいが➡
それと まったく逆の場合は
どうする？
But what if the exact opposite happens?
どういうことだ？
What does that mean?
さっき お前は➡
You just said you consider Sasuke
to be like a brother...
サスケを 兄弟のようだと言ったな？
ならば もし➡
What if Sasuke were to
attack the Leaf Village?
そのサスケが 木ノ葉を襲ってきたら
どうすると聞いているんだ。
What would you do then?
なんだ？ なんで サスケが…!?
What? Why would Sasuke...?
そんなことするわけねえだろ！
There's no way
he'd do something like that!
サスケは まだ純粋だ。
Sasuke is still naïve.
He can easily be dyed in any color.
簡単に 何色にでも染まる。
そうなった場合
お前は ヤツを止められるのか？
In such a case, can you stop him?
サスケを 殺してでも…。
Even if you have to kill Sasuke?
サスケと木ノ葉を
天秤にかけられるのか？
Could you weigh Sasuke
against the Leaf Village
on a set of scales?
木ノ葉は守る！
I would defend the Leaf Village!
そんでもって サスケも
殺さず止める！
But I would also stop Sasuke
without killing him!
子供だな。
You're such a child...
お前の話は 絵空事ばかりだ。
What you speak of are all fantasies.
忍は時に 厳しい選択を
迫られることだってある。
A ninja must sometimes make
very harsh decisions.
(自来也)サスケのことは
あきらめるんだのぉ。
You should give up on Sasuke.
遅かれ早かれ
こうなる運命だったんだ。
He was destined to leave,
sooner or later.
もう 苦しむな！
Don't suffer anymore...
忘れて 切り捨てろ！
Forget and dismiss him.
術や力だけじゃあない。
It's not just jutsu or power...
忍なら
正しい判断や選択をする目を養え。
If you're a ninja,
develop eyes that can make
the right judgment.
忍として生きるなら
もっと 賢くなれ！
And if you're going to live
as a ninja, become wiser.
バカのままじゃ この世界➡
This world...
It's no place for a fool.
That's the reality.
生きるのが つらいのが現実だ…。
わかったよ…。
Okay, I got it.
賢いってのが そういうことなら➡
If that's what being wise is,
I'd rather live my life as a fool.
オレは一生 バカでいい！
１人でも
もっとすげえ術 編み出して➡
Even if I have to do it alone,
I'll figure out a bigger, better jutsu
and rescue Sasuke.
サスケは ぜってえ助ける!!
前にも一度 同じことを言われた。
Someone told me that before...
でも 選択肢なんて ねえ！
But for me, there is no choice.
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ！
I never go back on my word...
それが オレの忍道だ！
That's my Ninja Way.
(イタチ)お前に
オレの力を分けてやった。
I have shared some of
my power with you.
その力…
使う日が来なければいいがな。
Though I hope the day
never comes
when you have to use it.
うっ… クッ…！
どういうことだってばよ…？
What's going on?
お前は… オレを狙ってたんだろ!?
Aren't you after me?
Then let's finish this!
だったら ここで…！
もう 行く…。
I'm going now...
(これから 大事な用があるんでな))
I have an important task to do.
《あん時…
イタチは 何を言いたかったんだ？
What did Itachi mean by that?
Why did he...?
何で オレに…》
((サスケの勝ちだよ！
うちはイタチは 死亡。
Sasuke has won.
Itachi Uchiha is dead.
サスケも倒れちゃったけど
どうだろう？
Sasuke's down too, but...
I wonder how he is?
(結構 ギリギリかも…))
He's in pretty bad shape.
お前… 今 どうしてんだ？ サスケ…。
What are you doing now, Sasuke?
無事だよな？
You're okay, right?
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
(重吾)大丈夫か？ サスケ。
Are you all right, Sasuke?
あぁ… 急ごう。
Yeah... Let's hurry.
もうすぐ 合流地点だ。
We're almost at
the rendezvous point.
約束どおり 八尾を連れてきた。
As promised,
I brought the Eight-Tails.
よくやったな。
お前ならやれると信じていた。
You did well. I had faith
that you could do it.
どこへ行く？
Where are you going?
まずは 傷を癒やす。
First, I'm going to tend
to my wounds.
それから 木ノ葉だ。
Then...
I'm going to the Hidden Leaf.
((マダラ : ひとつ 大切なことを聞く。
I'm going to ask
one important question...
イタチの生き様を知ったお前が
イタチの遺志を継ぎ➡
After learning about Itachi's life,
there is a chance
木ノ葉を守るという考え方もある。
that you will carry out his wish
and protect the Hidden Leaf.
本当のことを言え。
お前は どうしたい？
Tell me the truth.
What are your intentions?
イタチは オレに 命をかけて里を守る
生き様を見せてくれた。
Itachi showed me how
a man would give his life
to protect his village.
だが オレにとっては
そんな生き様よりも➡
But for me, the sadness
of losing Itachi
イタチを失った悲しみのほうが深い。
どうしようもなくな。
impacts me more deeply
than how he lived...
Unbearably more.
イタチを犠牲にした平和など
オレの望むものじゃない。
The peace that Itachi sacrificed
himself for isn't appealing to me.
真実を知った今➡
Now that I know the truth,
イタチの生き様を継ぎ
木ノ葉を守ることなど➡
following in Itachi's steps to
protect the Hidden Leaf
オレには 到底できない。
is the last thing I would do.
そして
上層部の３人は 絶対に許せない。
Most of all, I will never forgive
the three elders.
イタチの命を代償にして
ヘラヘラと平和を満喫している➡
And I believe that everyone in
the Hidden Leaf enjoying the peace
gained in exchange for
Itachi's life is guilty too.
木ノ葉の連中も同罪だ。
やるのは
上層部だけじゃなかったのか？
I thought you were only going
to kill the elders?
いや… オレ１人で
木ノ葉を 全員やりたいからな。
No... I wish to slaughter
the entire Leaf Village by myself.
鷹の前では そう言っただけだ。
I was just feigning in front of Taka.
それは 本当か？
Is that the truth?
あれだけの生き様を見せられて
イタチの遺志…。
After knowing just what
Itachi went through
to protect the village...
守ろうとしたものを
無にしていいと➡
Instead of carrying on his wish,
you'd destroy the village?
本気で そう思えるのか？
Are you serious?
アンタは 言ったな。
You said so yourself.
イタチが どうして
オレを殺せなかったのか？
The reason why Itachi couldn't
bring himself to kill me was...
イタチにとって オレの命は
里よりも重かったからだ。
he cherished my life more
than the village.
オレも同じだ。
オレにとって イタチの命は➡
I feel the same way.
Itachi's life is more precious
to me than the village.
里よりも重い。 それだけのことだ。
That's all.
うちはを差別し
両親を兄弟に殺めさせ➡
They shunned the Uchiha clan.
They forced my brother to
kill his own parents!
そのイタチを追い込み
殺した上層部も！
The elders who cast him out
and sealed his death!
そして 千手を慕う
木ノ葉の連中も！
And the rest of the Hidden Leaf
who abide by the Senju clan!
すべてが クソのはきだめだ！
They're nothing but scum!
すべてが 復讐の対象だ!!
They are all objects of
my vengeance!
オレを感情的に動くガキだと
バカにするなら それでもいい。
If you want to ridicule me as a brat
swayed by his emotions, go ahead.
イタチの遺志を受け入れるなど
きれい事だ。
Carrying on Itachi's wish are
merely pretty words.
憎しみを知らぬ者どもの戯言だ！
The foolish sputtering of those
who don't know hatred.
もし オレの生き様を
否定するようなヤツらがいるなら➡
If anyone criticizes my way of life,
ソイツらの大切な人間を
片っ端から殺してやる！
I'll kill every single one
of their loved ones!
そうすれば
少しは 理解するだろう。
Then they might understand a little...
(このオレの憎しみを))
...of the hatred I carry.
《マダラ : 人は 愛情を知ったとき
憎しみのリスクを背負う》
When a man learns to love,
he must bear the risk of hatred.
(雷影)なんだと！
キラービーが連れ去られたというのか？
What?!
Killer Bee was taken?!
襲撃者の中には 木ノ葉の➡
A member of the Hidden Leaf...
from the Uchiha clan
うちは一族の者も…。
was among the assailants.
今は 先輩が あとをつけています。
My partner is tailing them right now.
雷影様
どのようにいたしましょう？
Raikage-sama, what are your orders?
暁は許さんぞ！ 暁!!
The Akatsuki won't get away
with this!
The Akatsuki...!
我が弟よ 待っておれ！
Just you wait, my brother!
I realise the screaming pain
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Somber News
あ… なんだ カカシ先生か。
Oh, it's you, Kakashi-sensei.
五代目がお呼びだ。
すぐに支度しろ。
The Fifth has summoned you.
Let's go.
あれ？ ガマオヤビンにガマ吉。
Huh? Chief Toad and Gamakichi?
(ガマ吉)おう ナルト！
Yo, Naruto!
朝っぱらから
なんで こんなとこいんの？
What're you guys doing here
so early?
何かあったのか？
Did something happen?
実はのう…。
Actually...
(ブン太)ガマ吉！ オメエは
いらんこと言わんでええ！
Gamakichi! It's not your place
to say anything.
頭と 綱手に
任しとったらええんじゃ！
Leave this to the Boss and Tsunade.
いったい 何だってばよ？
いいから 行くぞ。
What's going on?
Just hurry up.
ん…。
(フカサク)この子が
自来也ちゃんの弟子か？
He is Jiraiya-chan's student?
(綱手)はい…
これが うずまきナルト。
Yes... This is Uzumaki Naruto...
その話の予言の子でしょう。
The "Child of Prophecy"
you mentioned.
じじいのカエル？ 何だ？
A geezer frog? What the hell?
コラ！ 口を慎め ナルト！
Hey! Watch your mouth, Naruto!
こちらは 妙木山の
二大仙人の１人 フカサク様だ。
This is Fukasaku-sama,
one of the Two Great Sages
of Mount Myoboku.
お前に用があって
わざわざ お越しになった。
He came all the way here
to speak with you.
正確には 二大仙蝦蟇じゃ…。
Well, to be more accurate,
I am a Great Sage Toad.
と… そんなことよりじゃ➡
But never mind that.
お前は 自来也ちゃんの弟子に
間違いないかいの？
You are, without a doubt,
Jiraiya-chan's student.
自来也ちゃん？ 「ちゃん」って
エロ仙人をガキ扱いかよ！
Jiraiya-chan? "Chan"?!
You talk as though
the Pervy Sage is a kid!
何なんだってばよ
このじじいガエル！
Who does this geezer frog
think he is?!
口を慎めと言ってるだろう！
I said to watch your mouth!
(シズネ)この方は 自来也様に
仙人術をお教えになられた➡
This great man is the one
who taught Sage Jutsu
to Jiraiya-sama.
自来也様の師です。
He is Jiraiya-sama's master.
ハハハハ… エロ仙人とはの…。
Pervy Sage, eh?
自来也ちゃんらしい
慕われ方じゃ。
What a fitting nickname
for Jiraiya-chan.
その じじい仙人が いったい
オレに何の用だってばよ？
So what does this geezer sage
want with me?
どっから話せばええのかの…。
I'm not sure where to begin.
そうじゃの…
とりあえず 言っておくが…。
But let's see...
I suppose
the most important thing is...
自来也ちゃんが戦死した。
は？
Jiraiya-chan has died in battle.
Huh?
な… 何言ってんだよ。
Wh-What are you talking about?
いきなりのことじゃ。
信じられんのも ムリはない…。
I know this is sudden.
I don't blame you if
you don't believe me.
少し前から 暁のリーダーが➡
For quite some time,
there were rumors
雨隠れの里に おるらしい
っちゅうウワサがあってな…。
that the leader of the Akatsuki
was in the Hidden Rain Village.
自来也ちゃんは自ら ウワサの真偽を
確かめに行ったんじゃ。
Jiraiya-chan went in person to
verify the truth of these rumors.
(サクラ)暁のリーダーが雨隠れに!?
The leader of the Akatsuki was
in the Hidden Rain Village?
(サイ)たしか あそこは
かなり潜入困難な…。
As I recall,
that village is difficult to infiltrate.
閉鎖的な里だったはずですよね。
A village closed to the outside world.
あぁ… しかし 自来也様は➡
Yes... However, Jiraiya-sama was skilled
潜入 諜報の術に
長けた方だからな…。
in infiltration and
espionage tactics.
そのとおり…。
Exactly...
((それが 自分で考えた
結論ですよ… 自来也先生))
That's the decision I've made...
Jiraiya-sensei.
(フカサク)自来也ちゃんは 暁のリーダー➡
Jiraiya-chan came upon
the leader of the Akatsuki... "Pain".
ペインのもとにたどり着いた…。
だが…。
((外見は
だいぶ変わったが その眼…。
However...
You look very different.
But those eyes...
やはり お前がペインだったか…
長門。
So you were Pain... Nagato!
正しい成長は
してないようだのぉ…。
It seems you've strayed off
the path of good.
何があった？
あなたは知らなくていい。
What happened?
You don't need to know.
After all, you are an outsider.
(しょせん 外の人間だ…))
ペインは 自来也ちゃんの
かつての教え子だったんじゃ…。
Pain was Jiraiya-chan's former student.
教え子って…
どういうことですか？
Student? What do you mean?
自来也ちゃんは
長門と呼んでおったが…。
Jiraiya-chan called him "Nagato".
ずいぶん昔のことだ。
忍界大戦の混乱の中…。
That goes way back.
During the chaos of
the Great Ninja War...
当時 戦場となった雨隠れで➡
Jiraiya looked after some orphans
in the Hidden Rain Village,
自来也は 身寄りのない
孤児の面倒を見ていたんだが…。
which had become a battlefield.
まさか
あのときの子供がな…。
Who would have imagined
that those kids...
しかし 自来也様ほどの
忍を追い込むとは➡
However...
To corner a ninja like Jiraiya-sama...
そのペインってヤツはいったい…。
How did this Pain...?
ヤツは 輪廻眼を持っとった。
なんですって？
He possessed the Rinnegan.
What did you say?!
輪廻眼？
Rinnegan?
輪廻眼は 忍の始祖とされる➡
The Rinnegan is an Ocular Jutsu
that was said to be possessed
by the father of all ninja,
六道仙人が持っていたといわれる
瞳術よ。
the Sage of the Six Paths.
神話レベルの話だと思っていたけど。
I thought it was just a legend.
伝説の瞳術 輪廻眼。
The legendary Ocular Jutsu...
The Rinnegan.
その能力は
想像を超えたものじゃった。
Its power was beyond imagination.
しかも…。
Not only that...
輪廻眼が６人も？
まさか そんなことが。
There were six of them
who possessed the Rinnegan?!
How can that even be possible?
何かカラクリがあるのかもしれん。
Perhaps, there's a trick to it.
おそらく あの場にいた
自来也ちゃんだけが➡
Most likely, only Jiraiya-chan,
who was there,
ヤツの秘密に気づいたんじゃ。 が…。
discovered their secret.
But...
((自来也ちゃん！))
Jiraiya-chan!
ペインとの戦闘で➡
Even after he had his throat
crushed by Pain,
喉を潰されてしもうた
自来也ちゃんは➡
最後にワシに
メッセージを残して倒れたんじゃ。
Jiraiya-chan left a message
before collapsing.
それが これじゃ。
This is that message!
暗号。
It's a code...
ペインに気づかれんよう
そうしたに違いない。
I'm sure he did this to prevent
Pain from noticing.
ここまでが
自来也ちゃんのすべてじゃ。
I've told you everything
about Jiraiya-chan.
自来也が何を伝えたかったのか。
I wonder what Jiraiya wanted to say.
それを解読すれば
わかるということですね。
If we can decode this...
we'll understand, won't we?
ばあちゃんが行かせたのか？
Did you... let him go, Granny?
そうだ。
That's right.
なんでそんなムチャ
許したんだってばよ。
Why'd you allow such
a reckless thing?!
ばあちゃんは エロ仙人の性格
よくわかってたんだろ！
You knew Pervy Sage better
than anyone!
たった一人でそんな
危ねえところに！
How could you send him to such
a dangerous place, alone?!
よせ ナルト。
Enough, Naruto.
五代目の気持がわからない
お前じゃないだろ。
You of all people ought to
know the Fifth's feelings.
((一人じゃ危険すぎる！
(自来也)ワシは木ノ葉の三忍だぞ。
It's too dangerous to go alone!
I am one of the Legendary Sannin
of the Leaf.
お前もその意味は
知っているだろう。
You know what that means as well.
美しかったお前も
今や五十のばばあ。
You were beautiful back then...
and now,
you're a fifty-something old granny.
死に別れた者たちへの思いが➡
It pains me to see how
all the memories
その大きな胸に詰まっているのか
と思うと やり切れんのう。
of your lost friends and loved ones
are stored inside that big breast of yours.
しかし それは この先も増える。
And you know,
the number will continue to grow.
だが しんみりするのは
ちと違うのう。
However... I guess I shouldn't
wallow in sadness.
ワシらの役目は 次の世代のために
手本となり手助けをすること。
My duty is to be a model for
the next generation
and to help them out.
そのためなら笑って命を懸ける。
For that, I'd happily give my life.
(それが年寄りのかっこよさ
というものだろうのう))
It's what makes us old folks cool, see?
クソッ。
Damn it!
ナルト。
Naruto!
どこいくの？
Where are you going?!
エロ仙人が
五代目火影になってたら➡
If Pervy Sage had been
the Fifth Hokage...
綱手のばあちゃんに こんなムチャは
させなかった。 ぜってえ。
he wouldn't have let Granny Tsunade
take such risks... Never!
ナルト。
サクラ… いい。
Naruto!
Sakura... It's all right.
Let him be.
少し そっとしておいてやれ。
でも…。
But...
すみません フカサク様。
ナルトとは いずれまた。
My apologies, Fukasaku-sama.
I'll arrange for Naruto to...
ああ。 それでええ。
No... That's all right.
さっき説明した
予言の子についてじゃけどの。
About the Child of Prophecy
I mentioned earlier...
あの子が自来也ちゃんを➡
I can see that child truly loved
and admired Jiraiya-chan.
まっすぐに慕っとったのが
ようわかった。
予言の子は
あの子であってほしいと➡
I can't help but hope that
he is the Child of Prophecy.
そう願わずにはおれんの。
((今からお前に教える。
口寄せの術だ。
I will now teach you...
the Summoning Jutsu!
うわぁ！
《この感じだ》
This is it!
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
(ワッ！))
Whoa!
((え～っ！ なんで!? なんで!?
Huh?!
Why? Why?!
なんで オレがエロ仙人と一緒に➡
Why do I have to go with
the Pervy Sage on a research trip?!
取材旅行なんかしなきゃ
なんねえんだってばよ！
ただの取材旅行じゃあねえのぉ。
It's not just a research trip.
取材したい女がいて
ソイツを捜さにゃならん。
There's a woman I want to research
and I must find her.
ねぇ！ ねぇ！
なんでオレ選んだの？
Say! Say!
Why did you choose me?
ワシはな 昔
四代目火影を弟子にしていてな。
Long ago...
I taught the Fourth Hokage.
(そんで お前は その四代目に
おもしろいくらい似てる))
And you have an uncanny
resemblance to him.
((時間は ムダには使わん。
I don't waste any time.
道中は すべて
お前に時間をあてるからのぉ。
During the journey,
you will have my undivided attention.
オレに？
Me?
(お前を強くする時間。 修業だ))
It's time to make you strong...
to train you!
here are the answers of the path
koko ni aru no wa kimi ga ima made erande michi no
you chose up till now, look and go on by yourself
kotae tachi yo hora jishin motte susumeba ii
it's very natural, like a rainbow over
totemo shizen na no amaeagari no
asphalt after a rainfall
asufaruto ni niji ga kakaru you ni
a lonely wind blew and
lonely kaze ga fuite
a feeling dawned on me
feeling ki ga tsuita yo
there's no answer anywhere
kotae wo doko ni mo nai kedo
call me, I got it already
call me wakatteru wa
with you, we'll always
with you ai wa itsu mo
love each other
atae au mono
for you
I'm sure one day you will
kitto kimi wa itsu no hi ka
be able to fly in the sky
kono sora wo toberu hazu dakara
no matter how many times we've stumbled for you
nando tsumaizuta to shite mo for you
there's only one thing important
taisetsu na koto wa hitotsu
which is to dream
yumemiru koto
so at least keep your heart open
kokoro dake wa tozasanaide ite
Next Episode
The boy wanders the village in despair,
(ナツ)『FAIRY TAIL』 前回までは…。
reminiscing about the memories with his late Master.
(ルーシィ)時計の部品を探す旅に
出た私たちは➡
砂漠の地下に広がる
墓所にたどり着いた。
The end of his childhood days approaches...
でも そこには 数々の罠が
張り巡らされていたの。
When all his grief is let out, the boy will rise up once again.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Following the Master's Shadow"
Following the Master's Shadow
After all, we can't stay brats forever.